让我们总结一下我们学到的一些东西：在这个讲座中我们谈到了空间
Let’s summarise some of the things we have learned: in this lecture we talked about spatial
图像处理运营商。
image processing operators.
这些操作是输出像素是相应周围的函数的地方
These operations are where the output pixel is a function of the corresponding surrounding
输入图像中的区域。
region in the input image.
我们讨论了边缘效应，以及输入窗口从边缘掉落的情况
We talked about edge effects and this where the input window falls off the edge of the
输入图像，我们需要某种策略来处理这个特定的问题。
input image and we need some sort of strategy to deal with this particular problem.
我们谈到了卷积;这是我们应用一个我们称之为内核的矩阵的地方
We talked about convolution; this is where we apply a matrix which we call a kernel to
使用卷积运算符的图像。
an image using the convolution operator.
我们可以使用它来执行一系列非常有用的图像处理功能，例如
We can use this to perform a raft of really useful image processing functions such as
平滑和梯度计算。
smoothing and gradient calculation.
我们研究了许多标准内核，例如Gaussian，它的衍生物
We looked at a number of standard kernels such as the Gaussian, the derivative of the
高斯和高斯拉普拉斯算子。
Gaussian and the Laplacian of Gaussian.
我们还研究了相关性。
We also looked at the correlation.
相关性类似于卷积;等式中的一些符号被改变了
Correlation is similar to convolution; some of the signs in the equation are changed and
如果内核是对称的，它相当于卷积。
it’s equivalent to convolution if the kernel is symmetric.
相关性对于模板匹配等任务非常有用，我们使用此技术进行查找
Correlation is useful for tasks such as template matching and we used this technique to find
机器人班德在一个非常繁忙的人群场景。
the robot Bender in a very busy crowd scene.
我们还讨论了非线性滤波器;我们讨论了排名和中位数过滤器并展示了如何
We also discussed non-linear filters; we talked about rank and median filters and showed how
它们有助于消除极端噪音。
they are useful for removing extreme noise.
我们还讨论了形态学图像处理，这是一种允许我们使用的技术
We also talked about morphological image processing, and this is a technique that allows us to
保留或删除基于其大小和形状的blob。
keep or remove blobs that are based on their size and shape.
如果你有一个小噪声斑点的图像，你可以简单地使用形态滤波器
If you have an image with small noise blobs you can use a morphological filter to simply
删除它们。
remove them.
或者，如果你有一个图像-也许是阈值处理的结果，那么对象有一些小的
Or if you have an image—perhaps the result of thresholding, the object has got some small
你不满意的洞-你可以使用形态处理来填补
holes in it that you are not happy about—you can use a morphological processing to fill
那些洞。
those holes in.